{"tossups": [{"question": "This man received an important command a ter a disgraceful treaty was signed by Gaius Hostilius Mancinus. Ruth Martin Brown argued that this man was at the center of a namesake intellectual \"circle\" including the writers Lucilius and Terence. During one battle, this general blockaded the Duero River with rotating logs embedded with spearheads, eventually forcing the besieged Celtiberians (kelt-\"eye\"-BEER-ee-ans) to commit mass suicide. This man's longtime friend, the Greek historian Polybius, accompanied him on the siege of Numantia in Spain. Polybius reports that this man \"shed tears\" and said \"a day will come when sacred Troy will perish\" after deserters threw themselves onto a  re in the citadel of Byrsa at the end of a 146 B.C. siege. For 10 points, name the Roman general who destroyed Carthage in the Third Punic War, an adoptive grandson of the victor of the Second Punic War.", "answer": "Scipio Aemilianus [or Publius Cornelius Scipio Aemilianus Africanus Numantinus; or Scipio Africanus the Younger; or Scipio Minor; or anything specifying the younger Scipio; prompt on Scipio; do not accept \"Scipio Africanus\"]", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Scipio Aemilianus</u></b> [or <b><u>Publius Cornelius Scipio Aemilianus Africanus Numantinus</u></b>; or <b><u>Scipio Africanus the Younger</u></b>; or <b><u>Scipio Minor</u></b>; or <b><u>anything specifying the younger Scipio</u></b>; prompt on <u>Scipio</u>; do not accept \"Scipio Africanus\"]", "acceptable": ["Scipio Aemilianus", "Publius Cornelius Scipio Aemilianus Africanus Numantinus", "Scipio Africanus the Younger", "Scipio Minor", "anything specifying the younger Scipio"], "promptable": ["Scipio"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Vedic sage Vasishta described this action as worse than killing a learned Brahmana and banned Brahmins and Kshatriyas from doing it. Debates about whether it is forbidden in modern Catholicism focus on the scope of Benedict XIV's 1745 encyclical Vix Pervenit. Ezekiel 18:13 states of someone who does this action that \"his blood shall be upon him,\" leading Jewish law to prohibit both marbit and neshek, two ways of doing it. In Islam, the takaful, sukuk, and most popularly, the murabaha \u0327 have arisen as halal alternatives to this practice, which is called riba and totally prohibited. Historically, Judaism and Christianity prohibited performing that practice only against fellow Jews and Christians, leading to the position of \"court Jew\" and the rise of the Rothschild family. For 10 points, name this practice which in modern Christianity has come to be de ned as \"usury\" only when it occurs at high rates.", "answer": "charging interest on a loan [or usury until it is read; prompt on moneylending]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>charging interest on a loan</u></b> [or <b><u>usury until it is read</u></b>; prompt on <u>moneylending</u>]", "acceptable": ["charging interest on a loan", "usury until it is read"], "promptable": ["moneylending"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This group wore silver pins shaped like battle standards inscribed with the quote \"WITHOUT EXTINCTION IS LIBERTY\" from Walt Whitman's \"By Blue Ontario's Shore.\" This group took refuge in Cameron House for two days a ter a crowd armed with guns took issue with a message ending \"Take the beam out of your own eye.\" Support for this group increased due to reports of how W.H. Whittaker ordered forty guards to smash them against iron beds or handcu f them to cell bars. Congressman Joseph Walsh gave a speech against this group ridiculing the \"demands of some iron-jawed angels.\" This group received repeated sentences of increasing duration for \"obstructing tra  c,\" one of which landed them in the Occoquan Workhouse to endure the \"Night of Terror.\" A  liated with Alice Paul's National Women's Party, this group protested for six days a week from 1917 to 1919 against the administration of \"Kaiser Wilson.\" For 10 points, name this  rst group to picket outside the White House, a group of protesters for women's su frage.", "answer": "the Silent Sentinels [or the \"iron-jawed angels\" before it is read; prompt on su fragettes; prompt on the National Women's Party]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the Silent Sentinels</u></b> [or the <b><u>\"iron-jawed angels\" before it is read</u></b>; prompt on <u>su fragettes</u>; prompt on the <u>National Women's Party</u>]", "acceptable": ["the Silent Sentinels", "\"iron-jawed angels\" before it is read"], "promptable": ["su fragettes", "National Women's Party"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Korpelevich's (kor-PEH-leh-vich's) extra\u00c2\u00b7gradient method  nds sequences that converge to these entities. Along with the hyperbolic property of orbits, a dynamical system must not have any connections between these entities for the system to be topologically stable, according to the Andronov-Pontryagin (pon-tree-AH-gin) criterion. In bifurcation theory, a periodic orbit colliding with one of these points will produce a homoclinic bifurcation. An extension of Laplace's method continuously changes a contour integral to pass nearby these points to approximate integrals. The equation \"z\" equals \"x cubed\" minus \"three x y-squared\" de nes a \"monkey\" surface that is itself de ned by one of these points, which correspond to inde nite Hessian matrices. These non-extremal objects have a derivative equal to zero. For 10 points, name these points at which a multi\u00c2\u00b7vari\u00c2\u00b7ate function simultaneously \"curves up\" and \"curves down.\"", "answer": "saddle points [or minimax point; prompt on stationary point; prompt on critical points]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>saddle points</u></b> [or <b><u>minimax point</u></b>; prompt on <u>stationary point</u>; prompt on <u>critical points</u>]", "acceptable": ["saddle points", "minimax point"], "promptable": ["stationary point", "critical points"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Description acceptable. In 2012, a seminal text on this phenomenon was criticized by James Forman, who cited Vanessa Barker's research on its \"politics.\" Marie Gottschalk has criticized narrow focus on \"non, non, nons\" in public discourse on this phenomenon. This phenomenon grew in a \"deadly symbiosis\" enabled by post-Fordism in an analysis by Loic Wacquant (loh-EEK wah-kwahn), who appended \"hyper-\" to its common name. Its e fects were analogized to a credentialing process in Devah Pager's account of a  eld experiment conducted in Milwaukee. It is the subject of a book that opens with a family history of Jarvious Cotton. O t-cited contributors to this phenomenon include a \"pipeline\" in the educational system and a namesake \"industrial complex\" in the private sector. For 10 points, identify this social problem discussed in Michelle Alexander's The New Jim Crow, whose title refers to the United States' skyrocketing inmate population.", "answer": "mass incarceration [or imprisonment; or anything mentioning jail; accept the New Jim Crow until \"Jim\"]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>mass incarceration</u></b> [or <b><u>imprisonment</u></b>; or <b><u>anything mentioning jail</u></b>; accept the <b><u>New Jim Crow until \"Jim</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["mass incarceration", "imprisonment", "anything mentioning jail", "New Jim Crow until \"Jim"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One player of this instrument published a book of scales and exercises and a book of fourteen etudes under the title Jazz Technic. Glenn Miller picked up arranger Jerry Gray a ter a player of this instrument dissolved his band and moved to Mexico. Joe Bishop co-wrote the song \"Woodchopper's Ball\" with a player of this instrument. Trumpeter Harry James started his career in a band led by a player of this instrument. A player of this instrument included songs like \"Loch Lomond,\" \"Bei mir bist du schoen\" (\"by\" MEER bihst doo SHERN), and \"Swingtime in the Rockies\" on his most famous album. Glenn Miller had Wilbur Schwartz play this instrument over four saxophones to create his distinctive sound. A player of this instrument scored a 1938 hit with his swing recording of Cole Porter's \"Begin the Beguine.\" Another player of this instrument featured Gene Krupa's drums in a 1938 Carnegie Hall version of \"Sing, Sing, Sing.\" For 10 points, name this instrument played by Woody Herman, Artie Shaw, and Benny Goodman.", "answer": "clarinets", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>clarinets</u></b>", "acceptable": ["clarinets"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this play, a man is instructed to crown bowls with freshly shorn wool before pouring out three drink-o ferings from a holy spring and laying olive sprays on the wet ground. A chorus in this play declares, \"Not to be born is best, but when a man has seen the light, the next best thing is to go back where he came from as fast as he can.\" This play provided the basis for T. S. Eliot's last play, The Elder Statesman. In this play, a man recognizes that his death is near a ter three successive peals of thunder and leads the way to his tomb. This play's protagonist trespasses on ground sacred to the Eumenides and curses his two sons who exiled him from his city when they both seek his aid in their civil war. In this play, Theseus rescues Ismene (iz-MEE-nee) from Creon's men and restores her to her blind suppliant father. For 10 points, name this play that makes up Sophocles's \"Theban trilogy\" along with Antigone and Oedipus Rex.", "answer": "Oedipus at Colonus [or Oedipus Coloneus; or Oidipous epi Colono]", "subcategory": "Classical Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Oedipus at Colonus</u></b> [or <b><u>Oedipus Coloneus</u></b>; or <b><u>Oidipous epi Colono</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Oedipus at Colonus", "Oedipus Coloneus", "Oidipous epi Colono"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One passage in this text ponders the nature of a \"thing,\" concluding that a deer, a beetle, or a blade of grass are not \"things\" but a stone and clod of earth are. It illustrates its idea of the \"copy-relation\" by reproducing C.F. Meyer's poem \"The Roman Fountain\" in its entirety. An imaginative reverie in this text evokes the \"silent call of the earth, its silent gi t of the ripening grain, its...self-refusal in the wintry  eld\" to show that reliability is the nature of equipment. This text argues that truth arises out of the \"strife between clearing and concealing in the opposition between World and Earth,\" and  nds the essence of truth in the Greek word aletheia (ah-LEE-thee-ah), meaning \"unconcealment.\" It largely deals with a concept called the Ursprung (OOR-shprung), literally meaning \"primal leap.\" It asserts that, unlike in tools, \"rock...becomes rock,\" \"colors...shine,\" and \"sounds...ring\" in both a Greek temple and a van Gogh painting of shoes. For 10 points, name this essay on aesthetics by Martin Heidegger.", "answer": "\"The Origin of the Work of Art\" [or \"Der Ursprung des Kunstwerkes\"]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\"The Origin of the Work of Art\"</u></b> [or <b><u>Der Ursprung des Kunstwerkes</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["\"The Origin of the Work of Art\"", "Der Ursprung des Kunstwerkes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This scientist is the namesake of a cosmological horizon that is equivalent to the event horizon of a Nariai (nah-ree-\"eye\") black hole. The inde nite special orthogonal group S-O four-comma-one replaces the Poincare\u0301 (pwahn-kah-ray) group as the symmetry group of spacetime in an alternative theory of special relativity named for this scientist. He is the namesake of the maximally symmetric vacuum solution of the Einstein  eld equations that has a negative cosmological constant. Juan Maldacena showed that a gravitational theory on that type of space named for this scientist corresponds to a conformal  eld theory de ned on its boundary. In general relativity, the presence of a non-rotating central mass requires a correction to the angular momentum of an orbiting body that is named for this scientist and is contrasted with frame dragging. For 10 points, identify this Dutch scientist who predicted the geodetic e fect, which is also known as his namesake precession.", "answer": "Willem de Sitter [accept de Sitter horizon or de Sitter invariant special relativity or anti-de Sitter space or de Sitter precession]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Willem de Sitter</u></b> [accept <b><u>de Sitter horizon</u></b> or <b><u>de Sitter invariant special relativity</u></b> or <b><u>anti-de Sitter space</u></b> or <b><u>de Sitter precession</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Willem de Sitter", "de Sitter horizon", "de Sitter invariant special relativity", "anti-de Sitter space", "de Sitter precession"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one of this author's books, British women style their hair in either ringlets or spit curls to show support for the opposing sides of the Turkish-Serbian War. One of the title characters of that book meets the other at a cricket match, but marries a doctor and eventually opens a chain of Montessori schools. This novelist, who charted the lives of her parents had they never married in Alfred and Emily, served as a sort of surrogate mother to a teenaged Jenny Diski a ter rescuing her from a toxic home. She wrote a novel in which Tommy's failed suicide attempt leaves him blind and causes him to turn to the socialist causes embraced by his mother Molly. The protagonist of that novel writes a diary focusing on her dreams and therapy, a novel titled Free Women, and a memoir of her experience in Southern Rhodesia. For 10 points, name this author who wrote about the life and writings of Anna Wulf in The Golden Notebook.", "answer": "Doris Lessing", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Doris <b><u>Lessing</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Doris Lessing"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In 2016, this speci c animal's name was given to a newly discovered spaceship in Conway's Game of Life that is only 28 cells and is the  rst to move at a speed of c over ten. Lionel Barrymore plays a farmer who is personally recruited by Abraham Lincoln in a 1920  lm named for this animal. To support Operation Bodyguard, Cli ton James made a public appearance in Gibraltar disguised as Bernard Montgomery in an operation of this name. A political faction named for this animal included the namesake of Ex Parte Milligan and was associated with societies called the Order of the Sons of Liberty and the Order of American Knights, which were o fshoots of the Knights of the Golden Circle. For 10 points, name this snake which lent its name of an Ohio-based faction of the Democratic party that advocated peace with the South and was led by Clement Vallandigham.", "answer": "copperhead [or copperhead spaceship; or The Copperhead, or Operation Copperhead; prompt on snake]", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>copperhead</u></b> [or <b><u>copperhead spaceship</u></b>; or <b><u>The Copperhead,</u></b> or <b><u>Operation Copperhead</u></b>; prompt on <u>snake</u>]", "acceptable": ["copperhead", "copperhead spaceship", "The Copperhead,", "Operation Copperhead"], "promptable": ["snake"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the Metamorphoses, this deity turns a race of horned men called the Cerastae (ker-ah-\"sty\") into bulls to punish their practice of human sacri ce. In the Argonautica, this deity narrates an ekphrasis describing a double-seamed golden ball overlaid with dark blue spirals. In the Aeneid, this deity interprets an omen of twelve swans that were scattered by an eagle but have now rejoined each other. In the Iliad, this deity listens to another deity tell stories such as the Aloadae imprisoning Ares in a jar and Heracles shooting an arrow into Hades' shoulder. In a Homeric Hymn to this deity, she claims to be a daughter of Otreus whom Hermes has abducted in order to seduce a man living on Mt. Ida in Phrygia (\"fridge\"-ee-ah). Zeus cripples that man with a thunderbolt a ter he brags about having sex with this deity, which is why her son has to carry him on his back during their escape from the sack of Troy. For 10 points, name this goddess, the mother of Aeneas.", "answer": "Aphrodite [or Venus]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Aphrodite</u></b> [or <b><u>Venus</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Aphrodite", "Venus"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem titled for some of these objects recalls how a drowned friend's angers were \"leeched away by the so t archery of summer rains and the sponge-paws of wetness\" and begins by describing \"Time that is moved by little  dget wheels.\" Five of these objects title an in luential blank verse elegy by Australian poet Kenneth Slessor. These objects \"engrave membrane through marrow\" in a poem whose speaker describes how one of them \"dispatches\" him \"to wander...from pit to cruci x, feet chill on steps from hell.\" These objects break down the structure that contains them in Hart Crane's \"The Broken Tower.\" Another poem describes the \"sort of Runic rhyme\" in which these silver, golden, brazen, and iron objects are \"keeping time, time, time.\" For 10 points, name these objects, the subject of an obsessive Edgar Allan Poe poem about their \"tintinnabulation.\"", "answer": "bells [accept bell-rope; prompt on rope]", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>bells</u></b> [accept <b><u>bell-rope</u></b>; prompt on <u>rope</u>]", "acceptable": ["bells", "bell-rope"], "promptable": ["rope"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Carolyn Dean analyzed how the Corpus Christi festival in this modern-day country became a site of resistance as it syncretized with summer solstice celebrations. A rebellion in this modern-day country arose from the belief that spirits were possessing people with a \"dancing sickness\"; that rebellion, the Taki Unquy (oon-kwee), was based on worship of spirits of inanimate objects like rocks and trees. In this country, a set of reforms limited the number of workers who could be conscripted to one seventh of a village's population under Viceroy Francisco de Toledo. In this country, where traditional worship of wakas  lourished, a rebel leader was forced to watch the execution of his wife Micaela Bastidas, then beheaded a ter a failed attempt to tear him apart with four horses. Exploitation of natives by corregidores (\"core\"-reg-ih-doh-\"race\") provoked the Tupac Amaru revolt in this modern-day country. For 10 points, name this country, a viceroyalty under the Spanish Empire that was also the heartland of the Inca.", "answer": "Viceroyalty of Peru", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Viceroyalty of Peru</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Viceroyalty of Peru"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Note to players: composer and type of piece required. In one of these pieces, a pianissimo Un poco meno mosso section begins with the right hand playing tenuto block chords over the le t hand's rapid arpeggiated D dominant seventh chord. In that one of these pieces, both hands punctuate the opening phrases with quick triple repetitions of G minor chords consisting of two sixteenth notes followed by an eight note. An Agitato section of one of these pieces begins with the right hand twice playing four triplets whose leading tenuto top notes are E, D-sharp, D-natural, C-sharp. A set of thirteen of these pieces concludes with pieces in G-sharp minor and D- lat major and makes up its composer's Opus 32. An Alla marcia one of these pieces in G minor is the   th in their composer's Opus 23. An E- lat minor Elegy and E major Melody in the composer's Morceaux de Fantasie (\"more\"-SOH deh FAHN-tah-ZEE)  lank a wildly popular one of these pieces in C-sharp minor. For 10 points, name these pieces for solo piano by the composer of Rhapsody on a Theme of Paganini.", "answer": "preludes by Sergei Rachmanino f [prompt on preludes for piano]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>preludes by Sergei Rachmanino f</u></b> [prompt on <u>preludes for piano</u>]", "acceptable": ["preludes by Sergei Rachmanino f"], "promptable": ["preludes for piano"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The gene that encodes the protein de cient in this disease also encodes a protein that triggers glucose release from the liver, the protein as\u00c2\u00b7pro\u00c2\u00b7sin. A series of thumb signs used to diagnose this disease are known as the Ghent criteria. The protein implicated in this disease is normally responsible for sequestering TGF-beta and formation of elastic  bers. A common result of this syndrome is myx\u00c2\u00b7o\u00c2\u00b7ma\u00c2\u00b7tous degeneration of the mitral valve leading to prolapse. The symptoms of this disease resemble those of Ehlers-Danlos (AY-lers dahn-lohs) syndrome, a similar connective tissue disorder. This autosomal recessive disorder is caused by a defect in a protein that surrounds elastin  bers known as  brillin. For 10 points, name this disorder characterized by an especially tall and thin appearance.", "answer": "Marfan syndrome [accept MFS]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Marfan syndrome</u></b> [accept <b><u>MFS</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Marfan syndrome", "MFS"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this century, 200 new monasteries were founded following the Hirsau Reforms devised by the monk William of Hirsau (rhymes with \"BEER now\"). During this century, Erlembald publicly smashed a cup consecrated by the palace chaplain Godefrey in a display of power for a lower-orders movement called the \"ragpickers.\" During this century, Peter Damian enumerated the forms of sodomy in his Liber Gomorrhianus (go-moh-ree-AH-nus). The Patarene (PAH-tah-reen) movement took over Milan during this century, in which the bull In Nomine Domini (in NOH-mee-nay DOH-mee-nee) restricted papal elections to the College of Cardinals. During this century, \"anti-king\" Rudolf of Swabia's death at the Elster ended the Saxon rebellion, which was endorsed by a longtime ally of Matilda of Tuscany. The issuer of the Dictatus Papae (dik-TAH-tus PAH-\"pie\") sought to root out clerical marriage and simony with namesake \"reforms\" during this century, forcing a recalcitrant emperor to wait for him in a hairshirt in the snow. For 10 points, name this century in which Gregory VII initiated the Gregorian Reforms and Henry IV walked to Canossa.", "answer": "Eleventh Century C.E. [or the 1000s C.E.]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Eleventh Century C.E.</u></b> [or the <b><u>1000s C.E.</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Eleventh Century C.E.", "1000s C.E."], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Particles of this element can be functionalized with RNA to modulate gene expression in vivo and are known as nano-beacons. Bacillus licheniformis (bah-SILL-us \"lie\"-ken-ih-FORM-iss) has been used to synthesize cubes of this element. An atom of this element bonded to a chlorine atom and tri\u00c2\u00b7phenyl\u00c2\u00b7phos\u00c2\u00b7phine in the GarGoyle complex. The number of atoms in mono-dispersed, thi\u00c2\u00b7o\u00c2\u00b7late-protected clusters of this element exhibit a pattern of magic numbers. The ability of this element to form complexes with itself in solution via the relativistic expansion of its d orbitals is commonly used for molecular self-assembly. Extraction of this element from ore begins by complexing it with cyanide. It's not platinum, but a solution of nitric and hydrochloric acid used to dissolve this element is known as aqua regia. For 10 points, name this element found below silver on the periodic table.", "answer": "gold", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>gold</u></b>", "acceptable": ["gold"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Note to players: artist and type of work required. Francis Bacon painted eight studies based on a destroyed example of one of these paintings, which depict a haunted zombie- gure with a shriveled shadow. A dedication scrawled \"to my friend\" is barely visible against a sea-green background at the top of one of these paintings in which the subject has shaved hair o f the sides of his head. One of these paintings, which uses rings of Pointillist-inspired uniform brushstrokes to create radiating halos in the background, shows its subject in a grey felt hat. Another of these paintings depicts a faceless man laden with boxes walking past a  eld on the way to Tarascon. A famous painting from this group depicts its subject in a heavy green overcoat and a fur-lined hat standing in front of a woodblock print of geishas. A dark blue background contrasts sharply with the subject's  ery orange hair in one of these paintings made at Saint-Remy (sahnt-reh-MEE). For 10 points, name this series of paintings by a Post-Impressionist artist, including one showing its creator \"with bandaged ear.\"", "answer": "the self-portraits of Vincent van Gogh", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the self-portraits of Vincent van Gogh</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the self-portraits of Vincent van Gogh"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A novel from this country begins with the protagonist recalling a shave he paid for with \"the hard-earned coins of his jail life.\" That novel from this country ends with the protagonist \"sagg[ing] down\" a ter saying \"I can feel it coming up under my feet, up my legs\u00c2\u2014.\" A novelist from this country wrote a series of journals that became the book My Dateless Diary while writing a novel whose story is told to Velan. A protagonist from this country falls in love with the dancer Rosie and possibly starves to death a ter being forced to fast to end a drought. The protagonist of a novel from this country loses three sons to a new tannery, is treated by the doctor Kenny, names her  rst daughter Irrawaddy, and is married to the farmer Nathan. The author of Nectar in a Sieve was from this country, as was a man who set novels including The Painter of Signs and The Guide in its  ctional town of Malgudi (mal-GUH-dee). For 10 points, name this country home to Kamala Markandaya (mar-kahn-\"DIE\"-uh) and R. K. Narayan (nah-\"RYE\"-un).", "answer": "Republic of India [or Bharat Ganarajya]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Republic of <b><u>India</u></b> [or <b><u>Bharat Ganarajya</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Republic of India", "Bharat Ganarajya"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Forces under this king lost a battle when they were  lanked by a nobleman who only realized there was a battle going on because of the loud cannon re. A rebellion against this king led to the death of the First Baron Saye and Sele (\"say and seal\"), but accomplished little else. The Battle of Formigny (for-min-yee) annulled the Treaty of Tours, in which this king failed to secure a dowry for his wife. The unpopularity of that treaty led to the banishment of his favorite advisor, William de la Pole, and the unsuccessful rebellion of Jack Cade. This king was deposed and  led to Scotland following the Battle of Towton. He had a mental breakdown a ter losing the city of Bordeaux, and reportedly spent the Second Battle of St. Albans laughing and singing. This husband of Margaret of Anjou was murdered a ter the Earl of Warwick's forces were defeated at the Battle of Tewkesbury. For 10 points name this king of England during the  rst phase of the Wars of the Roses, who was succeeded by Edward IV.", "answer": "Henry VI [prompt on Henry]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Henry VI</u></b> [prompt on <u>Henry</u>]", "acceptable": ["Henry VI"], "promptable": ["Henry"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}